When we have an issue and we ask for advice sometimes we can just come right out and say Could you give
当我们遇到问题并寻求建议时，有时我们可以直接出来说你能给吗？
me some advice.
我一些建议。
Then after our friend says Yeah sure we can say what we need advice about.
然后在我们的朋友说是的之后，我们可以说出我们需要的建议。
Sometimes we say this after Listen I'm having a problem with blah blah blah blah.
有时我们会在听完后说这句话，我对 blah blah blah blah 有问题。
Could you give me some advice please.
你能给我一些建议吗？
And then our friend can give us advice.
然后我们的朋友可以给我们建议。
Now again usually advice is something a little more serious.
现在再次通常建议是更严肃的事情。
It can be used for very simple things.
它可以用于非常简单的事情。
Should I wear the blue one or the red one.
我应该穿蓝色的还是红色的。
Give me some advice.
给我一些建议。
OK.
好的。
It's OK.
没关系。
Sure.
当然。
Sure we can do that but advice is a great word to describe somewhat more serious situations problems
当然我们可以做到，但建议是一个很好的词来描述一些更严重的情况问题
that we're facing in our lives.
我们在生活中所面临的。
Can you give me some advice please.
你能给我一些建议吗？
Or I could.
或者我可以。
That's an L..
那是L..
I could really use some or your advice.
我真的可以使用一些或你的建议。
I could really use some advice.
我真的可以使用一些建议。
I could really use your advice.
我真的可以使用你的建议。
I need some help.
我需要一些帮助。
I need some help can be used in lots of other situations.
我需要一些帮助可以在很多其他情况下使用。
Could be about I don't know carrying a sofa but I need some help.
可能是关于我不知道带沙发，但我需要一些帮助。
Could be asking for advice.
可以征求意见。
Listen my boyfriend broke up with me and said something really terrible.
听我的男朋友和我分手了，说了一些非常可怕的话。
I don't know what I should do.
我不知道我应该怎么做。
I need help.
我需要帮助。
I need advice.
我需要建议。
So there it's the same although help can be about many other things too.
所以它是一样的，尽管帮助也可以涉及许多其他事情。
Now to be more casual about it we could say I wonder if you could tell me what you think about so maybe
现在更随意一点，我们可以说我想知道你是否可以告诉我你的想法，所以也许
we're looking for a new job.
我们正在寻找一份新工作。
I wonder if you could tell me what you think about working at Google.
我想知道您能否告诉我您对在 Google 工作的看法。
Do you think it would be do you think it would be cool.
你认为它会是你认为它会很酷吗。
I wonder if you could tell me what you think about or you could just say this part.
我想知道您是否可以告诉我您的想法，或者您可以直接说这部分。
What do what do you think about me working at Google.
你觉得我在谷歌工作怎么样？
What do you think about me working that's whole.
你觉得我的工作怎么样？
That's a riff it's the worst one so far.
这是一首即兴演奏，是迄今为止最糟糕的一首。
Working at Google.
在谷歌工作。
OK.
好的。
So we can ask for advice in this way.
所以我们可以通过这种方式征求意见。
That's a little bit more a little bit more casual now as I mentioned advice can be kind of the same
现在有点随意了，因为我提到的建议可能是一样的
as a suggestion or a recommendation.
作为建议或建议。
So we could say could could you recommend some or you could say suggest here.
所以我们可以说你能推荐一些吗，或者你可以在这里说建议。
You could also say suggest maybe could you suggest some ideas for how our company can maybe deal with
你也可以说建议也许你能就我们公司如何处理提出一些想法
our financial problems.
我们的财务问题。
Could you suggest some.
你能推荐一些吗？
This one again.
又是这个。
Is it advice.
是不是建议。
Is it a suggestion OK.
这是一个建议好吗。
Maybe they're kind of very similar.
也许他们有点相似。
So it's OK if we use the word recommend or suggest when we're asking for advice that's totally ok.
因此，如果我们在寻求完全可以的建议时使用“推荐”或“建议”这个词是可以的。